Angshuman Mazumdar

I believe in a simple concept: if it's a piece of engineering, it is also a work of art. Also, an ardent follower of interactive media, especially video games, because they provide a great platform for experiences to flourish, unlike any other media.





angshuman.mazumdar@gmail.com



West Lafayette, Indiana



https://binaryvectorjr.github.io/

(585)-406-9165

in https://www.linkedin.com/in/angshuman-mazumdar-a0b75a130/



EDUCATION

Master of Science (Computer Graphics Technology)

Purdue University, West Lafayette (Indiana) August 2019 – Expected May 2021 (GPA – 3.96)

Capstone Project

Rochester Institute of Technology, Rochester (New York) January 2019 – May 2019

Bachelor of Technology (Electronics and Communication)

Vellore Institute of Technology, Vellore 2015 - 2019 (CGPA - 8.69)

High School and Senior School

Don Bosco Senior Secondary School, Guwahati 2003 - 2015 (93.4%)

WORK EXPERIENCE

Trainee

Bharti Airtel 05/2018 - 06/2018 Chandigarh, India Achievements/Tasks

> Automated data collection and organization process for SACFA Applicants (using Visual Basic for Applications) which reduced the time for data organization significantly.

Graphic Designer

MOX - Movement of Expression 02/2018 - 08/2019 Shillong, India Achievements/Tasks

Designed the logos for the event "Street Sangam"

• Involved in their design process for various events

Assistant Editor

The Power of Connection (Documentary) 05/2020 - Present West Lafayette (IN, USA)

ACHIEVEMENTS

Design Head (BEAM-VIT) (06/2016 - 05/2017)

BEAM-VIT was a club of VIT University. Also held the position of Design Co-Chair for BIDSF 2017. BIDSF is an annual event organized by the Biotech Division of VIT with the help of various clubs. Responsibilities included creating the theme, logo, posters and oversee various other design related issues for the event.

Design Advisor for Team Vimaanas (01/2017 – 06/2018)

Team Vimaanas is the official Micro-Class RC Aviation team of VIT. Responsibilities included helping them out with their design team by organizing their workflow, as well as teaching the members about graphic design, and redesigning their brochure.

SOFTWARE FAMILIARITY

Adobe Photoshop Adobe Illustrator Adobe Premiere Pro Adobe After Effects Unreal Engine 4 Unity3D World Machine Autodesk Maya Autodesk 3DS Max Blender Trimble SketchUp Houdini C++ HTML and CSS

Microsoft Office Suite (PowerPoint, Word, Excel)

MAJOR PROJECTS

Parkinson's Disease Assist Device using Machine Learning and Internet of Things (07/2017 - 04/2018)

- The main purpose of the project was to construct a prototype of a spoon which senses the hand motion of an individual suffering from Parkinson's disease.
- It gives a counter motion to the trembling actions of a patient's hand, in order that they don't spill their food.

Autonomous Robotic Manipulator (01/2019 – 04/2019)

- The goal was to develop the driver that will control a robotic arm manipulation of the larger project
- Final objective was to mount the arm to the top of an autonomous base, that could enable users to control it using Virtual Reality Techniques
- Application in the Elder Care Industry

Embodiment for the Difference: A VR Experience of Bipolar Disorder (08/2019 - 12/2019)

- The objective was to develop a simulation in virtual reality to provide an experience of the effects of Bipolar Disorder so as to make people aware of a few of the challenges a person suffering from bipolar disorder would have to face in their
- Platform used for delivering experience was Oculus Quest

LANGUAGES

| Assamese | Native Language |
|----------|--------------------------|
| English | Full Working Proficiency |
| Hindi | Bilingual Proficiency |
| French | Novice |